[
		{
			"question":"When Samson killed 1000 Philistines at Lehi what weapon did he use?",
			"answer":"Jawbone of an ass",
			"categories":["old_testament","judges"],
			"reference":"Judges 15:15"
		},
		{
			"question":"How old (years) was David when he was anointed King of Israel?",
			"answer":30,
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"2 Samuel 5:4"
		},
		{
			"question":"Aside from Peter and John, which disciple witnessed Jesus’ Transfiguration?",
			"answer":"James",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Matthew 17:1-2, Mark 9:2, Luke 9:28-29"
		},
		{
			"question":"In Damascus, whose sight was restored by Ananias?",
			"answer":"Saul",
			"categories":["new_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Acts 9:17-18"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many rivers were formed from the river that went out of Eden?",
			"answer":4,
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 2:10 (Pishon, Gihon, Hiddekel, and Euphrates)"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the name of the place where Jacob slept and dreamed of Jacob's Ladder?",
			"answer":"Bethel",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 28:19"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who told Naaman to wash in the river Jordan 7 times in order to cure his leprosy?",
			"answer":"Elisha",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","miracles"],
			"reference":"2 Kings 5:10"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who announced to Zachariah that his wife would bear a child to be named John the Baptist?",
			"answer":"Angel Gabriel",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Luke 1:13"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who said, '…as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord'?",
			"answer":"Joshua",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Joshua 24:15"
		},
		{
			"question":"What does the name 'Emmanuel' mean?",
			"answer":"God with us",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Matthew 2:23"
		},
		{
			"question":"God tested Abraham by telling him to offer his only son as a burnt offering. Who was that son?",
			"answer":"Isaac",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 22:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many pieces of silver was Judas paid to betray Jesus?",
			"answer":30,
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 26:15"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who personally baptized more people, Jesus or John the Baptist?",
			"answer":"John the Baptist",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"John 4:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who witnessed Elijah being taken up to Heaven?",
			"answer":"Elisha",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","miracles"],
			"reference":"2 Kings 2:11-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"Only 2 persons in the Bible are reported as being 'taken up to Heaven' (instead of dying). One is Elijah. Who is the other?",
			"answer":"Enoch",
			"categories":["old_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Genesis 5:24"
		},
		{
			"question":"Only 2 persons in the Bible are reported as being 'taken up to Heaven' (instead of dying). Who are they (in chronological order)?",
			"answer":"Enoch and Elijah",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","miracles"],
			"reference":"Genesis 5:24, 2 Kings 2:11-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who hid Joshua’s spies from Jericho’s king?",
			"answer":"Rahab",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"Joshua 2:1-4"
		},
		{
			"question":"Moses died at age 120 and was buried in a valley of Moab. Who buried him?",
			"answer":"The Lord",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","prophets"],
			"reference":"Deuteronomy 34:6"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many years were the Israelites in bondage in Egypt?",
			"answer":430,
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus"],
			"reference":"Exodous 12:40-41"
		},
		{
			"question":"When they heard of the adversity that had befallen Job, how many of his friends came to comfort him?",
			"answer":3,
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Job 2:11"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who is the only woman mentioned in Paul’s letter to Philemon?",
			"answer":"Apphia",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Philemon 2"
		},
		{
			"question":"What part of the day did Christ embark on the boat from which He calmed the waters?",
			"answer":"Evening",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Mark 4:35"
		},
		{
			"question":"After his epiphany, how many years did Paul spend in Arabia before beginning his ministry?",
			"answer":3,
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Galatians 1:18"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many troops did Sennacherib lose at the siege of Jerusalem?",
			"answer":185000,
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"2 Kings 19:35"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who was the father of John the Baptist?",
			"answer":"Zacharias",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Luke 3:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many demons came out of Mary called Magdalene?",
			"answer":7,
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Luke 8:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"When the multitude came out to be baptized, how did John the Baptist characterize them?",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"answer":"Brood of vipers",
			"reference":"Luke 3:7"
		},
		{
			"question":"From what tribe of Israel did the Apostle Paul come?",
			"answer":"Benjamin",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Philippians 3:5"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who directed Paul to preach to the Gentiles?",
			"answer":"Jesus",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Acts 26:17"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who was the king of Israel when David slew Goliath?",
			"answer":"Saul",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 17"
		},
		{
			"question":"To whom did God describe Job as a perfect and upright man?",
			"answer":"Satan",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Job 1:8"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who said, “Silver and Gold have I none, but such as I have I give thee?”",
			"answer":"Peter",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Acts 3:6"
		},
		{
			"question":"James, the brother of John, was the first Apostle martyred. How was he killed?",
			"answer":"With a sword",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Acts 12:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"How old (in years) was Abraham when his son Isaac was born?",
			"answer":100,
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 21:5"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the title placed on Jesus’ cross?",
			"answer":"King of the Jews",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Luke 24:38, John 19:19"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who took his rod and stretched out his hand upon the waters of Egypt to turn them into blood?",
			"answer":"Aaron",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","prophets","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7:19-20"
		},
		{
			"question":"Where (city) were the disciples first called Christians?",
			"answer":"Antioch",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Acts 11:26"
		},
		{
			"question":"When Jesus struggled with his cross, who was forced to bear it for him?",
			"answer":"Simon from Cyrene",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Mark 15:21; Matthew 27:32"
		},
		{
			"question":"According to the Book of Revelations, what needs to be done to receive the crown of life?",
			"answer":"Faithful until death",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Revelations 2:10"
		},
		{
			"question":"What body of water, other than the red sea, was parted in the Bible?",
			"answer":"Jordan river",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"By Joshua (Joshua 3:7-4:18), and by Elijah and Elisha (2 Kings 2: 2-8 and 13-14)"
		},
		{
			"question":"How tall was Goliath?",
			"answer":"6 cubits and a span",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 17:4"
		},
		{
			"question":"What did Paul say was the fulfillment of the Law?",
			"answer":"Love",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Romans 13:10"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the shortest chapter in the Bible?",
			"answer":"Psalm 117",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Psalm 117 (2 verses)"
		},
		{
			"question":"There are only two perfect cubes described in Scripture. What is the one described in Revelation?",
			"answer":"New Jerusalem",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Revelation 21:16"
		},
		{
			"question":"God parted the Red Sea so Moses and the Israelites could cross. What body of water did He part so Joshua and the Israelites could cross?",
			"answer":"Jordan River",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Joshua 3:15-17"
		},
		{
			"question":"At Christ’s crucifixion what time of day did darkness come over the whole land?",
			"answer":"Noon",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 27:45"
		},
		{
			"question":"At Christ’s crucifixion darkness come over the whole land. How long did it last?",
			"answer":"3 hours",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 27:45"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many persons were sealed as 'servants of our God on their forehead'?",
			"answer":"144,000",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Revelations 7:4"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the name of the City of God?",
			"answer":"New Jerusalem",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Revelations 3:12"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who was the father of David?",
			"answer":"Jesse",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"Ruth 4:22"
		},
		{
			"question":"To which king did Isaac hide his spousal relationship with Rebecca by claiming she was his sister?",
			"answer":"Abimelech",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 26: 1-9"
		},
		{
			"question":"3 named women found Christ’s tomb open and empty: Mary Magdalene, Mary the mother of James, and _____?",
			"answer":"Joanna",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Luke 24:10"
		},
		{
			"question":"3 named women found Christ’s tomb open and empty: Joanna, Mary the mother of James, and _____?",
			"answer":"Mary Magdalene",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Luke 24:10"
		},
		{
			"question":"3 named women found Christ’s tomb open and empty: Mary Magdalene, Joanna, and _____?",
			"answer":"Mary",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Luke 24:10 (the mother of James)"
		},
		{
			"question":"To which tribe of Israel did Moses belong?",
			"answer":"Levi",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","prophets"],
			"reference":"Exodus 2:1"
		},
		{
			"question":"To what land did Moses flee after killing the Egyptian soldier?",
			"answer":"Midian",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","exodus"],
			"reference":"Exodus 2:15"
		},
		{
			"question":"Christ’s first miracle was turning water into wine. Where did this occur?",
			"answer":"Cana of Galilee",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"John 2:6-9, 11"
		},
		{
			"question":"Sarah was Abraham’s first wife. Who was his second?",
			"answer":"Keturah",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 25:1"
		},
		{
			"question":"What relic did Moses remove from Egypt at the time of the Exodus?",
			"answer":"Bones of Joseph",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","exodus"],
			"reference":"Exodus 13:19"
		},
		{
			"question":"How old was Abraham when he was circumcised?",
			"answer":99,
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 17"
		},
		{
			"question":"After Christ’s triumphal entrance into Jerusalem and after visiting the temple, where did he spend the night?",
			"answer":"Bethany",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Mark 11:11"
		},
		{
			"question":"The first two disciples selected by Jesus were brothers. Name them in alphabetical order (____ and ____).",
			"answer":"Andrew and Simon",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Mark 1:16"
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of the tribes of Israel was prohibited from owning land in Canaan?",
			"answer":"Levites",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Deuteronomy 18:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"What city is called the City of David?",
			"answer":"Bethlehem",
			"categories":["old_testament","new_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"Luke 2:4"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who ate honey out of a lion’s carcass?",
			"answer":"Samson",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"Judges 14:5-9"
		},
		{
			"question":"What famous city did Nebuchadnezzar rule?",
			"answer":" Babylon",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"??"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who was Israel’s first high priest?",
			"answer":"Aaron",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","exodus"],
			"reference":"Exodus 28"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who is the only woman whose age is mentioned in the Bible?",
			"answer":"Sarah",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 23:1"
		},
		{
			"question":"Which books in the Bible are named after women? (____ and ____, in order of appearance in the Bible)",
			"answer":"Ruth and Esther",
			"reference":"Ruth and Esther",
			"categories":["old_testament"]
		},
		{
			"question":"How many Jews were exiled to Babylon by Nebuchadnezzar?",
			"answer":4600,
			"reference":"Jeremiah 52:30",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"]
		},
		{
			"question":"When Moses was preparing the Israelites for their coming confrontation with the 7 nations of Canaan, how large an army (number) did he raise?",
			"answer":603550,
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"Numbers 1:46"
		},
		{
			"question":"When God finally let the Israelites enter the promised land of Canaan, how many nations had to be destroyed?",
			"answer":7,
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus"],
			"reference":"Acts 13:19"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who leapt in his mother’s womb when Mary visited?",
			"answer":"John the Baptist",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Luke 1:41"
		},
		{
			"question":"After the 5000 ate their fill of the 5 loaves and 2 fishes, how much food was left over?",
			"answer":"12 baskets",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Matthew 14:20"
		},
		{
			"question":"On the 7th day, how many times did Joshua’s army march around Jericho before the walls fell?",
			"answer":7,
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Joshua 6:5"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who did God describe as 'a blameless and upright man'?",
			"answer":"Job",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Job 1:8"
		},
		{
			"question":"Aside from the Serpent, what other animal in the Old Testament spoke to humans?",
			"answer":"Donkey",
			"categories":["old_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Numbers 22:28-30"
		},
		{
			"question":"Whose flock was Moses tending when he encountered the burning bush?",
			"answer":"Jethro",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 3:1"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who said, 'Silver and gold have I none; but such as I have I give thee'?",
			"answer":"Peter",
			"categories":["new_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Acts 3:6"
		},
		{
			"question":"How long was Jonah in the belly of the great fish?",
			"answer":"3 days and 3 nights",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets"],
			"reference":"Jonah 1:17"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many days did Joshua’s troops march around Jerico before the walls fell?",
			"categories":["old_testament","miracles","exodus"],
			"answer":7,
			"reference":"Joshua 6:3-5: Hebrews 11:3"
		},
		{
			"question":"Where is King David buried?",
			"answer":"City of David",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"1 Kings 2:10 (aka Old Jerusalem)"
		},
		{
			"question":"At the transfiguration who appeared and talked to Christ? (____ and ____, in their respective order in the Bible)",
			"answer":"Moses and Elijah",
			"reference":"Matthew 17:3; Mark 9:4; Luke 9:30",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","prophets"]
		},
		{
			"question":"How many Beatitudes are there?",
			"answer":8,
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 5:3-10"
		},
		{
			"question":"How old (in years) was Noah when the flood was upon the earth?",
			"answer":600,
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 4:6"
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of Joseph’s (coat of many colors) 11 brothers said to his brothers not to kill Joseph but to cast him in a pit instead?",
			"answer":"Reuben",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 37:21-22"
		},
		{
			"question":"Paul said he would visit the Romans on this journey to which country?",
			"answer":"Spain",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Romans 15:24"
		},
		{
			"question":"How old (years) was Adam when he died?",
			"answer":"130",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 5:3"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many times was Peter told to forgive his brother who had sinned against him?",
			"answer":"Seventy times seven times",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 18:22"
		},
		{
			"question":"After his epiphany on the road to Damascus, how many days was Saul without sight?",
			"answer":3,
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Acts 9:9"
		},
		{
			"question":"Where is Moses buried?",
			"answer":":Valley of Moab",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus"],
			"reference":"Deuteronomy 34:6 (in the valley)"
		},
		{
			"question":"About how long was Christ on the cross before he said “My God, my God, why hast thou forsaken me?”",
			"answer":"9 hours",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 27:46"
		},
		{
			"question":"How old was Moses when he died?",
			"answer":"120",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus"],
			"reference":"Deuteronomy 34:7"
		},
		{
			"question":"According to Paul in Romans, how many righteous people are there? (number)",
			"answer":0,
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Romans 3:10"
		},
		{
			"question":"Adam and Eve had 3 sons. Cain was the firstborn followed by Abel. Who was the third son?",
			"answer":"Seth",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 4:25"
		},
		{
			"question":"To whom did Jesus say, 'Man shall not live by bread alone.'?",
			"answer":"Satan",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 4:4"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many loaves and fishes did Jesus use to feed the multitude of 5000? (__ loaves and ___ fishes)",
			"answer":"5 loaves and 2 fishes",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Mark 6:41; Matthew 14:17; John 6:9; Luke 9:13"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the name of the city founded by Cain?",
			"answer":"Enoch",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 4:17"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many days had Lazarus been dead before being risen by Jesus?",
			"answer":4,
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"John 11:39"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many devils were cast out of Mary Magdalene?",
			"answer":"7",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels","miracles"],
			"reference":"Luke 8:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"What did John the Baptist eat while preaching in the Judean wilderness?",
			"answer":"Locusts and wild honey",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 3:4"
		},
		{
			"question":"Name the mountain from which Moses viewed Canaan and on which he died.",
			"answer":"Nebo",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Deuteronomy 32: 49-50"
		},
		{
			"question":"For refusing to worship a false god, Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego were cast into a fiery furnace by King Nebuchadnezzar. How many times hotter than normal did the king order the furnace fire to be?",
			"answer":7,
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","miracles"],
			"reference":"Daniel 3:19"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who is the only Gentile in the Bible to be identified as the Lord’s anointed?",
			"answer":"Cyrus",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"Isaiah 45:1 [King of Persia 580 BC – 529 BC]"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the shortest verse in the Bible?",
			"answer":"Jesus wept",
			"reference":"John 11:35",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"]
		},
		{
			"question":"In Genesis two men are identified as having walked with God. Who are they? (____ and ____, alphabetical order)",
			"answer":"Enoch and Noah",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 5:24 and Genesis 6:9"
		},
		{
			"question":"Jacob and Esau were twin brothers. Name their father and mother respectively. (____ and _____)",
			"answer":"Isaac and Rebecca",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 25:19"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who negotiated with God to not destroy Sodom if but 10 righteous people could be found there?",
			"answer":"Abraham",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 18: 23-32"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the 1st plague God inflicted on Egypt?",
			"answer":"River waters turned to blood",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the 2nd plague God inflicted on Egypt?",
			"answer":"Frogs",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the 3rd plague God inflicted on Egypt?",
			"answer":"Lice",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the 4th plague God inflicted on Egypt?",
			"answer":"Flies",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the 5th plague God inflicted on Egypt?",
			"answer":"Death of animals",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the 6th plague God inflicted on Egypt?",
			"answer":"Boils",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the 7th plague God inflicted on Egypt?",
			"answer":"Hail",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the 8th plague God inflicted on Egypt?",
			"answer":"Locusts",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the 9th plague God inflicted on Egypt?",
			"answer":"Darkness",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the 10th plague God inflicted on Egypt?",
			"answer":"Death of first-born son",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many plagues did God inflict on Egypt?",
			"answer":10,
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus","miracles"],
			"reference":"Exodus 7-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many books are in the New Testament?",
			"answer":27,
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"-nil-"
		},
		{
			"question":"Which city was Jesus entering when Zacchaeus climbed a sycamore tree to see him?",
			"answer":"Jericho",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Luke 19:1-4"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the longest chapter in the Bible?",
			"answer":"Psalm 119",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Psalm 119 (176 verses)"
		},
		{
			"question":"Where did Cain go when he left Eden?",
			"answer":"Nod",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 4:16"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who replaced Judas as the twelfth apostle?",
			"answer":"Matthias",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Acts 1:15-26"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the most common name in the Bible?",
			"answer":"Zechariah",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"-nil-"
		},
		{
			"question":"Of what were the 12 gates of New Jerusalem made?",
			"answer":"Pearls",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Revelations 21:21"
		},
		{
			"question":"Name Jezebel’s husband.",
			"answer":"Ahab",
			"reference":"1 Kings 16:31",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"]
		},
		{
			"question":"Which timber was used to construct the Ark of Noah",
			"answer":"Gopher",
			"reference":"Genesis 6:14",
			"categories":["old_testament"]
		},
		{
			"question":"Name Moses’ brother",
			"answer":"Aaron",
			"reference":"Exodus 7:1",
			"categories":["old_testament"]
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the age of Moses (years) at the time of his demise?",
			"answer":"120",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Deuteronomy 34:7"
		},
		{
			"question":"In the Bible, God is said to have physically written thrice – each time on a different surface. On what did his writing appear at the third instance?",
			"answer":"Wall",
			"categories":["old_testament","miracles","prophets"],
			"reference":"Dan 5:5-12"
		},
		{
			"question":"Balaam was spoken to by which animal?",
			"answer":"Donkey",
			"categories":["old_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Numbers 22:22-35"
		},
		{
			"question":"What prophet issued ominous warning against people who took advantage of widows and the fatherless?",
			"answer":"Malachi",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets"],
			"reference":"Malachi 3:5"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who did Mordecai refuse to bow down to?",
			"answer":"Haman",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Esther"
		},
		{
			"question":"How old in years was Moses when he died?",
			"answer":"120",
			"categories":["old_testament","exodus"],
			"reference":"Deuteronomy 34:7"
		},
		{
			"question":"How long was Daniel in the den of the lions?",
			"answer":"1 night",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","miracles"],
			"reference":"Daniel 6"
		},
		{
			"question":"What animal is mentioned most frequently in both the New and Old Testaments?",
			"answer":"Sheep",
			"categories":["old_testament","new_testament"],
			"reference":"-nil-"
		},
		{
			"question":"How much time did Jonah spend in the belly of the whale?",
			"answer":"3 days and 3 nights",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets"],
			"reference":"Jonah 1:17"
		},
		{
			"question":"What biblical Babylonian king cast Daniel into the lion’s den for praying to God in defiance of a royal decree?",
			"answer":"Darius the Mede",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","kings_judges","miracles"],
			"reference":"Daniel 6"
		},
		{
			"question":"According to the Bible, what weapons was the Philistine giant, Goliath carrying when he was slain by David? (_____ and _____)",
			"answer":"Sword and spear",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 17:45"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the longest name in the Bible? (no need to type in the dashes)",
			"answer":"Maher-shalal-bash-baz",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Isaiah 8:1"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who came to Zechariah to tell him that his wife would soon be having a baby?",
			"answer":"Angel Gabriel",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Luke 1:19"
		},
		{
			"question":"According to the Bible, how many pearly gates are there?",
			"answer":"12",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Revelation 21:12-21"
		},
		{
			"question":"In the Bible, which of the 4 horsemen of the Apocalypse rides a red horse?",
			"answer":"War",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Revelation 6:1-8"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the colour of the horse which the 'War' horseman of the Apocalypse rides?",
			"answer":"Red",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Revelation 6:1-8"
		},
		{
			"question":"In the Bible, which of the 4 horsemen of the Apocalypse rides a pale/ashen horse?",
			"answer":"Death",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Revelation 6:1-8"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who tells the disciples that Jesus had risen from the dead?",
			"answer":"Mary Magdalene",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 28:1-10, John 20:1-10"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many times did Peter deny Jesus?",
			"answer":3,
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 26:33-35, Mark 14:29-31, Luke 22:33-34, John 13:36-38"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who fled from Iconium when they heard of a plot to stone them? (___ and ____, alphabetical order)",
			"answer":"Barnabas and Paul",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Acts 14:5-6"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who was the first king of Israel?",
			"answer":"Saul",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 10:1"
		},
		{
			"question":"What kind of tree did Zacchaeus climb to see Jesus enter Jericho?",
			"answer":"Sycamore",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Luke 19:1-4"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who was able to decipher Nebuchadnezzar’s dreams?",
			"answer":"Daniel",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","kings_judges","miracles"],
			"reference":"Daniel 2"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who was Joseph’s master in Egypt as stated in Genesis 37:36?",
			"answer":"Potiphar",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 37:36"
		},
		{
			"question":"Name the disciple who was a tax collector.",
			"answer":"Matthew",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 10:3, Mark 2:14, Luke 5:27"
		},
		{
			"question":"What king of Judah was stricken with leprosy?",
			"answer":"Uzziah",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"2 Kings 15:5 (also known as Azariah)"
		},
		{
			"question":"What king of Israel had a reputation as a fast and furious chariot driver?",
			"answer":"Jehu",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"2 Kings 9:20"
		},
		{
			"question":"What occurred when Jonathan and his armor-bearer attacked the Philistines?",
			"answer":"Earthquake",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges","miracles"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 14:11-15"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who built the first altar?",
			"answer":"Noah",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 8:20"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many shekels did Abraham pay to buy the field of Machpelah?",
			"answer":400,
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 23:16"
		},
		{
			"question":"After he fled for his life, which tree did Elijah sleep under?",
			"answer":"Juniper",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"1 Kings 19:5"
		},
		{
			"question":"Judas betrayed Jesus for exactly how many coins of silver?",
			"answer":30,
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Matthew 26:15"
		},
		{
			"question":"Name David’s father",
			"answer":"Jesse",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 17:12"
		},
		{
			"question":"God is not mentioned in only 1 book of the Bible. Which one?",
			"answer":"Esther",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Esther"
		},
		{
			"question":"For how many pieces of silver was Joseph sold by his brothers to the Ishmeelites?",
			"answer":20,
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 37:28"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many apostles did Jesus choose?",
			"answer":"12",
			"categories":["new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Luke 6:13"
		},
		{
			"question":"The angel said to Mary that Jesus would 'reign over the house' of which Old Testament character?",
			"answer":"Jacob",
			"categories":["old_testament","new_testament","gospels"],
			"reference":"Luke 1:33"
		},
		{
			"question":"Which prophet said, 'Out of Egypt have I called my son'?",
			"answer":"Hosea",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets"],
			"reference":"Hosea 11:1"
		},
		{
			"question":"What type of tree did Jesus curse?",
			"answer":"Fig",
			"categories":["new_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Mark 11:12-14"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who did Saul request a medium bring up for him?",
			"answer":"Samuel",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 28:11"
		},
		{
			"question":"Which Psalm is the verse “He makes me lie down in green pastures, he leads me beside quiet waters,” from?",
			"answer":"23",
			"categories":["old_testament","psalms_"],
			"reference":"Psalm 23:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"The fear of the Lord is the beginning of...?",
			"answer":"Wisdom",
			"categories":["old_testament","proverbs","psalms"],
			"reference":"Psalm 111:10, Proverbs 9:10"
		},
		{
			"question":"What city did the Lord tell Jonah to preach against?",
			"answer":"Nineveh",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets"],
			"reference":"Jonah 1:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of these books (Philippians, Colossians, Galatians or Ephesians) come first in the Bible?",
			"answer":"Galatians ",
			"categories":["new_testament","letters_of_paul"],
			"reference":"Contents page"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many chapters does the book Hebrews have?",
			"answer":"13",
			"categories":["new_testament","letters_of_paul"],
			"reference":"Hebrews 1-13"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the name of the storm winds which can hit Crete?",
			"answer":"Euroklydon",
			"categories":["new_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Acts 27:14"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many baskets were left over from the feeding of the 5000?",
			"answer":"7",
			"categories":["new_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Matthew 15:3"
		},
		{
			"question":"Which disciple found a coin in the mouth of a fish?",
			"answer":"Peter",
			"categories":["new_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Matthew 17:24-27"
		},
		{
			"question":"What did Peter find in a fish's mouth?",
			"answer":"Coin",
			"categories":["new_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Matthew 17:24–27"
		},
		{
			"question":"In which book of the bible to we read about Haman?",
			"answer":"Esther",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Esther 3"
		},
		{
			"question":"Name the only female judge mentioned in the Bible",
			"answer":"Deborah",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"Judges 4:4"
		},
		{
			"question":"Name the wife of King Agrippa, which Paul stood before on trial?",
			"answer":"Bernince",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Acts 25:23"
		},
		{
			"question":"How old did Enoch become?",
			"answer":"365",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 5:23"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who was the oldest person recorded in the Bible?",
			"answer":"Methuselah",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 5:27"
		},
		{
			"question":"How old was the oldest person recorded in the Bible?",
			"answer":"969",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 5:27"
		},
		{
			"question":"What does Jahwe-Schammah mean?",
			"answer":"God himself",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets"],
			"reference":"Ezekiel 48:35"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many more years did God add to King Hezekiah's life in response to the dying king's prayer?",
			"answer":"15",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"2 Kings 20:6"
		},
		{
			"question":"What prophetess of the Lord did King Josiah of Judah consult?",
			"answer":"Huldah",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"2 Kings 22:14-16"
		},
		{
			"question":"What ceremony did King Josiah reinstate that had not been celebrated by any of the previous kings of Israel or Judah?",
			"answer":"Passover",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"2 Kings 23:21"
		},
		{
			"question":"Upon the return of the ark to Israel, what sacrifice did Samuel offer to the Lord?",
			"answer":"Suckling lamb",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 7:9"
		},
		{
			"question":"Name Samuel's firstborn son",
			"answer":"Joel",
			"categories":["old_testament","prophets"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 8:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"Of what tribe of Israel was King Saul",
			"answer":"Benjamin",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 9:21"
		},
		{
			"question":"What was the name of king Saul's wife?",
			"answer":"Ahinoam",
			"categories":["old_testament","kings_judges"],
			"reference":"1 Samuel 14:50"
		},
		{
			"question":"What is required for anyone to understand God's Word?",
			"answer":"Holy Spirit",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"1 Corinthians 2:11"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who did Paul say judged him?",
			"answer":"God",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"1 Corinthians 4:4"
		},
		{
			"question":"___ deferred makes the heart sick?",
			"answer":"Hope",
			"categories":["old_testament","proverbs"],
			"reference":"Proverbs 13:12"
		},
		{
			"question":"On the Day of Pentecost there came a sound from Heaven of a rushing mighty _____?",
			"answer":"Wind",
			"categories":["new_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"Acts 2:2"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who offered to pay money for the power to give the Holy Spirit?",
			"answer":"Simon",
			"categories":["new_testament"],
			"reference":"Acts 8 (Simon the Sorcerer)"
		},
		{
			"question":"When Jesus turned water into wine, he converted water that was in stone jars. What we’re these stone jars normally used for?",
			"answer":"Ceremonial washing",
			"categories":["new_testament","miracles"],
			"reference":"John 2:6"
		},
		{
			"question":"How many books in the Bible have the name “John” in the title?",
			"answer":"4",
			"categories":["new_testament","letter_of_paul"],
			"reference":"John, 1 John, 2 John, 3 John"
		},
		{
			"question":"Which book in the Bible has the shortest title?",
			"answer":"Job",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Job"
		},
		{
			"question":"What were the names of the three sons of Noah in the order the Bible lists them in?",
			"answer":"Shem, Ham and Japheth",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 9:18-19, 1 Chronicles 1:4"
		},
		{
			"question":"Who was Nimrod’s father?",
			"answer":"Cush ",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"1 Chronicles 1:10"
		},
		{
			"question":"What were the names of Abraham’s two sons (in order of birth)?",
			"answer":"Ishmael and Isaac",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 16:1-16, 21:1-7, 1 Chronicles 1:28"
		},
		{
			"question":"The Lord changed Abraham’s name to Abraham when he was ninety-nine years old, what was his name before that?",
			"answer":"Abram",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 17:1-5"
		},
		{
			"question":"How old was Abraham when Isaac was born?",
			"answer":"100",
			"categories":["old_testament"],
			"reference":"Genesis 21:5"
		}
]
